<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description>Personal website built on the dbyll theme.</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Imposter Syndrome and Other Conference Hangover Ramblings</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I go to a lot of conferences. Partially to learn new things, partially to see old and make new friends, but mostly to re-up my motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the daily grind of being a professional software developer it’s easy to get caught up in the minutia and struggles of life and forget why you got into programming to begin with.Conferences always remind me that I got into this to solve problems, help people and have a voice. Having just returned from RailsConf 2017 in beautiful Phoenix, AZ I am again, excited about programming and excited to achieve my goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I always am after conferences. So, in an effort to not let this post conference high turn into another post conference hangover, I’m resurrecting this blog, and thereby, my resolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solving-problems&quot;&gt;SOLVING PROBLEMS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talks at RailsConf cover a wide variety of topics but they all hold to one common theme: problem solving. Whether solving the problem of subpar performance, broken hiring practices or understanding how much your cat poops (thanks for that one, Aaron) developers never ceases to amaze me with their curiosity innovation and sense of humor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At work I get to solve problems for customers and it’s a real joy when I can show them how to solve problems for themselves. But I want to get better at identifying my own problems (like the fact that I am pretty subpar at databases) and improving them. I also want to get better at following up on opportunities for improvement I see around me instead of just saying “wouldn’t it be nice if” and then continuing on with my life. So to that end I am also going to make this the year that I finally get involved in open source software. Which brings me to my next point…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;helping-people&quot;&gt;HELPING PEOPLE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people just don’t have time to contribute to open source. They’re up to their eyeballs in work, learning, and family obligations. I’m at a season in my life where, realistically, I could have a fair enough amount of time to help out in the community if I just shook off the fear I have of seeming stupid. I’ve been a professional software developer for going on 2 years and while I know my limitations I know I am smart and capable. That doesn’t stop me from having imposter syndrome or being afraid to look foolish when I ask questions. Multiply this by the potential of EVERYONE on the internet potentially seeing my questions or posts and it’s mildly horrifying. What if I misunderstand something and my question is just completely ridiculous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only real way I’ve found to overcome this fear is to remind myself that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Far more mediocre people than me — probably mostly white guys, sorry, not sorry — fearlessly ask very stupid questions all the time without giving them a second thought and they seem to survive;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is nothing new under the sun so someone else out there somewhere interpreted the information the way I did or had the same question and I am helping them by saying something;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most developers aren’t even trying or interested in contributing so I really don’t care what they have to say.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve, of course, not completely abandoned my dream of helping/giving back just because I haven’t yet written the greatest open source code ever. I’ve been on the Rails Girls Atlanta board for over a year now and put on 2 amazing workshops! Being a part of RGATL was very important to me because that was where I really discovered web development, the ruby community and the amazing community of women developers here in Atlanta. To them I am eternally grateful. This journey has changed my life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other ways I have given back, and I encourage you to as well, are volunteering at conferences, participating in guide/mentor programs, coaching workshops and getting involved in local student groups. I’m also loaning my technical skills to my church. Find something you care about and ask how you can get involved. I promise you’ll love it and you’ll feel more involved!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-my-voice&quot;&gt;USING MY VOICE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, my blog wasn’t update for almost 2 years before this post. There are a lot of reasons for that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not wanting to offend my coworkers with my critiques of various processes/coding styles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overly critical of my own post ideas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not making it a priority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last one is really the biggie. If you don’t make something a priority you won’t do it. And if you do, it won’t be very good. I come from a background in journalism and I love to write. I love to make videos. I love to create. I also have a lot of opinions. This should be a great setup for a great blog/vlog. But I just haven’r prioritized writing. As such I feel that I have lost my voice. The more you put yourself out there; the more you speak up, the more comfortable you get doing so. It’s scary to put your inner voice on the internet for all to see. But the more you do it the more normal it feels. Or at least, so I tell myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke at a conference last year and it was terrifying. But it was worth it. So I’m going to write more. I’m going to speak more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get ready for lots more of me all over the internet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-tldr-on-this-post&quot;&gt;What’s the TL;DR on this post?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first 2 years as a developer I’ve gotten complacent in the reasons I got into this industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t wanna be complacent anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m gonna start blogging again!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll be speaking at more conferences!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m also going to become a super official open source contributor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If none of those things happen by next RailsConf, you have permission to call me out on it when you see me at the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/general/2017/04/30/conference-hangover.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/general/2017/04/30/conference-hangover.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>If you want something sometimes all you need to do is ask</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I randomly decided that I wanted to get all of my STARS Computing Corps students to a software conference. I wanted them to see that there is an entire awesome world of modern technology outside of our tiny corner of Georgia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sent an email specifically asking for free tickets to a Connect.JS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise I received a response back almost immediately. After speaking with the contact I was offered a set of passes. Then I needed a way to get the students to the conference. I emailed our faculty sponsor and BOOM Travel and Lodging funds were offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am only posting this to say that if you want something just ask for it. Best case you’ll get it and worse case they say no and you are no worse than when you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YOLO&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/general/2015/09/17/just-ask.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/general/2015/09/17/just-ask.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>STARS Respect 2015</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I had the opportunity to attend the &lt;strong&gt;10th annual STARS Celebration of Diversity in Computing.&lt;/strong&gt; This conference was colocated with IEEE’s 1st annual &lt;strong&gt;Research on Equity and Sustained Participation in Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;, Computing and Technology (RESPECT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus of these conferences was on boradening participation in computing through education, research and outreach. I was privileged to present my poster &lt;em&gt;“Tech Girls Shine”&lt;/em&gt; at RESPECT and gice a talk on “Leveraging Partnerships to Fund Outreach Events” at STARS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very encouraging to see how other schools and communities are reaching out and getting women and minorities interested in computing careers. I was also excited to gain some new tools to bring back to CSU for our own outreach events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to leave you all with the best quote from the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”[Underrepresentation] is not a women’s problem. It is not a minority problem. It is a national problem and we all need to work together to solve it regardless of race or gender.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/general/conferences/2015/08/18/stars2015.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/general/conferences/2015/08/18/stars2015.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to secure funding for your computing outreach event</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;On April 25, 2015 Columbus State University STARS Computing corps hosted Tech Girls Shine, a day of computing for 3rd through 5th grade girls in underserved schools. But we couldn’t have done it on our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first get the idea for an outreach event it can be very exciting. But once you start dealing with the logistics it can be very daunting. The total cost for our event was about $3,000. Our budget was $0. But we were still made it happen. And you can too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;funding-sources&quot;&gt;Funding sources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grants&quot;&gt;Grants&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, grants. The government, non-profits and even corporations have money set aside for community service, education and outreach. Our event was targeted at women in computing so we looked for grants that focussed on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncwit.org/programs-campaigns/ncwit-awards/ncwit-student-seed-fund&quot;&gt;NCWIT Student Seed Fund&lt;/a&gt; This is the rant we applied for and received. They provice $1000 to support events which encourage women to enter STEM disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anitaborg.org/awards-grants/pass-it-on-awards-program/&quot;&gt;Anita Borg Pass it on Awards&lt;/a&gt; These are variable value grants ($500-$1000) for the purpose of furthering the involvement of women in computing. They can be used for events or for individual research of conference attendance&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;organizations-with-similar-goals&quot;&gt;Organizations with similar goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are passionate about reaching out to a specific group about computing, chances are someone else is too. And if you are lucky, that someone might have the money to help fund your event! There are 3 types of organizations you should look to for funding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Businesses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-profits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Student Organizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses have a stake in encouring more involvement and diversity in computing. More technology professionals means more talent for them to choose from. Find the big tech chompanies and web development shops in your community and see if they would be willing to donate, provide a location or supply equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is likely a non-profit organization in or near your community with a similar target demographic as your event. Tech Girls Shine partnered with a local organization called Empowered Youth of Columbus which provides educational resources for children in low income communities. They helped us find children who could benefit from our program, provided transportation and showed up to the event as extra volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not you are in school, if there is a loal univversity you should reach out to student organizations interested in the same cause you are. For our event we worked with 2 student organizations outside our own. Our local ACM chapter provided volunteers and $600 for t-shirts for the event. The Student Government Association gave us $1429 for the purchase of 10 Kano computer kits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-educational-resources&quot;&gt;Free Educational Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucky for you there are TONS of free educational resources online. Below is a list of just a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scratch.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;Scratch&lt;/a&gt; Learn programming concepts and make cool games!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.touchdevelop.com/&quot;&gt;Touch Develop&lt;/a&gt; Create Windows Phone applications, like flappy bird!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://appinventor.mit.edu/explore/&quot;&gt;App Inventor&lt;/a&gt; Create Android applications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeacademy.com&quot;&gt;Code Academy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hackety.com/&quot;&gt;Hackety Hack&lt;/a&gt; Learn Ruby in a fun online IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/general/2015/08/13/outreach-resources.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/general/2015/08/13/outreach-resources.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sometimes I power through 2 weeks worth of Ruby tutorials in one night...</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I enrolled on the SkillCrush Ruby Developer Blueprint which is technically supposed to start today. Well, addict that I am, I’m already through week 2. To be fair, I have already learned most of what was covered in those sections but it was a good review and I learned some interesting meta information about Ruby and its community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skillcrush separates it’s Blueprints into 3 one-month courses. This course is specifically focused on the Ruby language, the seond course is focused on Sinatra and ActiveRecord and the third is focused exclusively on Rails. I think I am most excited about the Sinatra and ActiveRecord section as I am least familiar with these but I think the Rails course looks like ti will go deeper than I have gone before and I am excited to produce some new projects!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for my little website here, it is still a work in progress but Jekyll and GitHub pages made it SUPER fast to push out a good looking blog. The Jekyll installation is lightweight and fast and there are numorous themes available to install. You can use them as is to get a good looking product or you can use them as a starting point like I did. This them (dbyll) was great but the color scheme wasn’t quite ME. I also wanted to add a few pages and Jekyll is so simple and straight forward that I didn’t need ANY documentation to figure out where my new pages needed to live.  I think I’d like to start building some jekyll themes of my own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great day, internet!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/general/ruby/2015/08/10/skillcrush.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/general/ruby/2015/08/10/skillcrush.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>First post!</title>
				<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-want-to-be-a-web-developer&quot;&gt;I want to be a web developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, I want to be a * Ruby on Rails * developer. This site is dedicated to documenting that journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site, like me, is currently a work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/general/ruby/2015/08/09/set-post.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/general/ruby/2015/08/09/set-post.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
