<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description>Personal website built on the dbyll theme.</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Sometimes I power through 2 weeks worth of Ruby tutorials in one night...</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I enrolled on the SkillCrush Ruby Developer Blueprint which is technically supposed to start today. Well, addict that I am, I’m already through week 2. To be fair, I have already learned most of what was covered in those sections but it was a good review and I learned some interesting meta information about Ruby and its community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skillcrush separates it’s Blueprints into 3 one-month courses. This course is specifically focused on the Ruby language, the seond course is focused on Sinatra and ActiveRecord and the third is focused exclusively on Rails. I think I am most excited about the Sinatra and ActiveRecord section as I am least familiar with these but I think the Rails course looks like ti will go deeper than I have gone before and I am excited to produce some new projects!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for my little website here, it is still a work in progress but Jekyll and GitHub pages made it SUPER fast to push out a good looking blog. The Jekyll installation is lightweight and fast and there are numorous themes available to install. You can use them as is to get a good looking product or you can use them as a starting point like I did. This them (dbyll) was great but the color scheme wasn’t quite ME. I also wanted to add a few pages and Jekyll is so simple and straight forward that I didn’t need ANY documentation to figure out where my new pages needed to live.  I think I’d like to start building some jekyll themes of my own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great day, internet!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/general/ruby/html/css/2015/08/10/skillcrush.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/general/ruby/html/css/2015/08/10/skillcrush.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>First post!</title>
				<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-want-to-be-a-web-developer&quot;&gt;I want to be a web developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, I want to be a * Ruby on Rails * developer. This site is dedicated to documenting that journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site, like me, is currently a work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/general/ruby/rails/2015/08/09/set-post.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/general/ruby/rails/2015/08/09/set-post.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
